ideo.com 2019-09-27

# IDEO Privacy Policy | ideo.com

This Privacy Policy and certification seal located on our Sites confirm that we are a valid licensee, and participating member, of the [Entertainment Software Rating Board’s Privacy Certified Program](http://www.esrb.org/privacy/faq.aspx#10) _(“ESRB Privacy Certified”)_. To help protect your privacy, we have voluntarily undertaken this privacy initiative. As a licensee in this privacy certification program, we are subject to audits of our Sites and other enforcement and accountability mechanisms administered independently by ESRB Privacy Certified. Our Sites containing the ESRB Privacy Certified seal have been reviewed and certified by ESRB Privacy Certified to meet established online information collection and use practices

Depending on the IDEO Site you are using, or where you contact us, your information is stored on the servers of our service providers, including Rackspace, Amazon Web Services, and Heroku. Please note that information we collect from you may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which we or our service providers maintain facilities. We or our service providers may transfer information that we collect about you, including Personal Information across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. We encourage you to review [Heroku](https://www.heroku.com/policy/salesforce-heroku-msa), [Amazon Web Serv](https://aws.amazon.com/service-terms/)[ices](https://aws.amazon.com/service-terms/), and [Rackspace’](https://www.rackspace.com/en-nl/legal/generalterms)s terms of service agreements and privacy policies before providing information to them. 

We use reasonable physical, procedural, technical and administrative security measures to protect your Personal Information against loss or theft as well as unauthorized access and disclosure to protect your privacy. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not retroactively reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent, and we expect most such changes will be minor. For future changes, we will notify you of any material changes in the way we collect, use, or share your Personal Information by sending you an email at the last email address that you provided us, or by prominently posting notice of the changes on the Site(s) covered by this Privacy Policy, or providing other appropriate notices required under applicable law. We will also post the new Privacy Policy to the Sites, which you are advised to consult regularly for any changes. Each version of this Privacy Policy will be identified at the bottom of the page by its effective date. 

**_IDEO Network Account Registration and Sign on_**

*Please note if you registered for our products before April 2018 this process may not apply to you. On March 27th, 2018, IDEO began a process of consolidating access to some of its Sites under one global secure login account process, which will give Users access to a network of IDEO services, and for those Users who participate individually or under a Client contract to more than one IDEO Site, one convenient login for the IDEO Network (an “ **IDEO Network Account** ”). If the service you want to access has been consolidated under this process you will see a general IDEO registration page when you register or login. If the Site you are accessing has not yet been integrated into the IDEO Network Account process, you will be directed straight to that individual Site. 

**Account Creation & Profile: **To register for an IDEO Network Account, you must provide your email address, first name, last name, and you will be asked to choose a secure password. As part of this process, you will be given an “IDEO Network Profile”. 

If you register for an IDEO Network Account using Facebook or Google the following information, if it has been made publicly available by you, will be stored on our servers as your login information: Facebook or Google ID, first and last name, email address, country, profile photo, geo-location, gender and date of birth. Additionally, your Facebook, or Google Profile Picture becomes part of your login Information but is not stored by us. Your use of information by Facebook or Google in this context will be set out more fully in their privacy policies and in accordance with the settings you choose using their sites. 

**Deletion of Your IDEO Network Account:** If you wish to delete your Personal Information from the IDEO Network, please contact [privacynotice@ideo.com](mailto:privacynotice@ideo.com) **.**

**_OI Engine_**

OI Engine is the name of IDEO’s software platform (the “ **OI Platform** ”) used to leverage the ideas, learnings and power of the crowd. The OI Platform is the underlying software which powers OpenIDEO and The Teacher’s Guild. The OI Platform isand Shape are also used by our Clients’ organizations to leverage their internal or limited access communities (“OI Engine **Private Platforms** ”). As a User of OI Engine, you are obliged to comply with applicable privacy laws in your use of other people’s Personal Information as stated in the terms of use, including but not limited to that of other Users, and other individuals whose information such as images, names, quotes and other Personal Information you use on OI Engine.

**_Shape_**

Shape is the name of IDEO’s software platform for small teams and large organizations alike to collaborate on new ideas, share knowledge, obtain feedback, and test prototypes with customers (“ **Shape** ”). Shape is also used by our Clients’ organizations to leverage their internal or limited access communities (“ **Shape** **Private Platforms** ”). As a User of Shape, you are also obliged to comply with applicable privacy laws in your use of other people’s Personal Information as stated in the terms of use, including but not limited to that of other Users, and other individuals whose information such as images, names, quotes and other Personal Information you use on Shape.

As part of the Shape Feedback function, Users can obtain feedback on ideas and concepts and receive aggregated anonymous feedback based on the same. Shape does not provide and does not want to receive Personal Information through the Feedback function. In some cases, Users can create a bespoke Feedback survey which allows for freeform questions and responses. You must not request or solicit the Personal Information of any respondent through the Feedback function directly or indirectly. 

In order to build our growing community of respondents to provide anonymised and useful feedback for our Shape Users, Shape may ask individuals if they would like to be contacted for future opportunities. Where respondents opt in to this opportunity, their Personal Information (such as contact information, information about personal preferences and interests) may be stored by IDEO and will be used to contact relevant respondents to give feedback for certain opportunities.

**_OpenIDEO_**

In addition to your IDEO Network Account, Users of OpenIDEO will have an OpenIDEO profile which can be viewed in the “My Profile” section of the Site. Once you register (either for the individual Site using the directions on the site, or via your IDEO Network Account), create My Profile, or submit a Contribution you are not anonymous to us (and may be visible to other Users depending on the activity). As only Users can submit a Contribution on the Site, if you choose to submit a Contribution prior to registering to the Site, we will require you to first (i) register with your Login Information thus creating My Profile and, if applicable, (ii) agree to any Challenge Rules or if applicable, any Alliance guidelines. 

Please note that if you register for OpenIDEO using Facebook, or Google the following information, if it has been made publicly available by you, will be stored on our servers as your login information: Facebook or Google ID, first and last name, email address, country, profile photo, locale, gender and date of birth. Additionally, your Facebook, or Google Profile Picture becomes part of your login Information but is not stored by us. Your use of information by Facebook or Google in this context will be set out more fully in their privacy policies and in accordance with the settings you choose using their sites. 

All Contributions will be viewable by other Users of the Site. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to register or submit a Contribution or Applause. If you choose to submit Contributions or Applause, or post messages on the Site, we will collect and store the information you provide to us. If you delete your account on the Site, your User data will be removed from the Site and your My Profile will be deleted, however your posts and comments may still be visible under the alias “Inactive User.” 

It is each User’s decision as to whether they add Personal Information to their My Profile section or upload a photograph/image of themselves and opt to make these visible to other Users as part of My Profile. The image/photo/picture, first and last name, gender and date of birth from Facebook or Google (if used) can be deleted at each User’s discretion. Your Facebook or Google ID is not visible in My Profile but can appear in your My Profile URL. 

My Profile will include your Design Quotient. Your **“Design Quotient”** (or **“DQ”** ) is a profile of you that we derive based on your Contributions, other Users’ feedback on your Contributions, and your “Applauding” of other User Contributions (as defined in the OpenIDEO [Terms of Service](https://challenges.openideo.com/terms)[)](https://challenges.openideo.com/terms) of other Users’ Contributions. Your DQ is published on the Site, accessible on each page of the Site, and visible to other Users unless you choose to make it private (an option available in My Profile). 

“ **Chapters** ” are groups of individuals who choose to arrange themselves geographically to solve challenges, work more deeply on areas within a challenge, or just meet for community purposes. Chapter organizers are volunteers selected by IDEO to run certain Chapters. If you RSVP for an event organized by a Chapter through the Site, your name and photo will be added to the event registrants list unless you choose to show as an anonymous attendee in My Profile. (Event creators and Organizers will still have access to your name and email unless you choose not to attend an Event. Event creators and Organizers are prohibited from use of Personal Information for anything other than their Chapter head duties related to the event). 

**Challenge and Alliance Sponsor:** IDEO challenges or alliances are promoted, sponsored by and championed, by sponsors (“ **Challenge or Alliance Sponsor** ”). A Challenge or Alliance Sponsor (other than IDEO) cannot store or disclose your Personal Information; this can only be done by IDEO in compliance with this Privacy Policy. IDEO may share information that you have entered in My Profile with a Challenge or Alliance Sponsor to analyze Users’ Contributions, comments and Applause for the Challenge or Alliance Sponsor’s own Challenge(s) or Alliance(s). **Chapter Organizers:** IDEO does not give a Chapter Organizer any authority to store or disclose your Personal Information; this can only be done by IDEO in compliance with this Privacy Policy. In addition, and as stated above, Chapter Organizers may have access to your Personal Information, but they are under strict obligations to use that information only for purposes related to their Chapter head duties.

**_Teachers Guild_**

IDEO and Riverdale Country School ( **“Riverdale”** ) own and operate [www.teachersguild.org](http://www.teachersguild.org/) (“ **The Teachers Guild** ”). 

In addition to your IDEO Network Account (if you registered through the IDEO Network Account process), Users of The Teachers Guild will have a Teacher’s Guild profile which can be viewed in the “My Profile” section of the Site. Your Login Information is held within My Profile. 

If you register on the Teachers Guild using ‘Facebook Connect’ or ‘Google Connect’ then the following information, if it has been made publicly available by you, will be stored on our servers as your Login Information: – Facebook or Google ID, first and last name, email address, country, locale, gender and date of birth. Additionally, your Facebook or Google Profile Picture becomes part of your Login Information but is not stored by us. Your Facebook or Google ID will be your Username for the Teachers Guild. 

In addition to your email address and Login details, you also have the option of entering additional information such as school, subject, grade level taught, number of years teaching, city, state, and social media which we would use to tailor and localize the User experience as well as tracking impact from the Collaborations (as defined in the Teachers Guild [Terms of ](https://www.teachersguild.org/terms)[Use](https://www.teachersguild.org/terms)). 

It is each User’s decision as to whether they add personal information to My Profile or upload a photograph/image of themselves and opt to make these visible to other Users as part of My Profile. The image/photo/picture, first and last name, gender and date of birth from Facebook or Google (if used) can be deleted at each User’s discretion.

My Profile will include your Design Quotient. Your “Design Quotient” (or “ **DQ** ”) is a profile of you that we derive based on your Contributions, other Users’ feedback on your Contributions, and your Applause of other Users Contributions. Your DQ is published on the Site, accessible on each page of the Site, and visible to other Users unless you choose to make it private (an option available in My Profile). 

If you wish to contribute or participate in the Site, you must (a) register with the Teacher’s Guild, and (b) become an Entrant by agreeing to the Collaboration Rules. All Contributions will be viewable by other Users of the Site. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to register or submit a Contribution or Applause. 

**Other Corporate Entities** : We may share our data, including your Personal Information, Non-Identifying Information and Log Data, with Riverdale, and with Riverdale’s affiliates’ companies. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their Users. To the extent allowed by applicable law, these entities follow privacy practices that are no less protective of Users than the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

IDEO and Riverdale may use behavior analytics to drive site performance, including process, review, copy, report and/or distribute Analytic Quotient Information. “ **Analytic Quotient Information** ” means data generated by the Site including but not limited to: 

  * Participation levels of Users by category (including but not limited to: organizational department; seniority; gender); 
  * Industry sector of Site Controller; Size of Site Controller entity by number of Users of the Software, turnover or number of employees; Level and nature of collaboration between Users; 
  * Level and format of device impact of Users (such as desktop computer, mobile device); Time spent by Users on Site; and 
  * Behavior of Users on individual functions of the Software, and any feature of the Site; Impact of bugs or Software errors on User activity. 

Where Analytic Quotient Information is disclosed to or accessed by any third party (except IDEO, Riverdale, and Riverdale subcontractors including third party providers of tools who may have access), any Personally Information will be anonymized and aggregated.

**_The Purpose Project_**

IDEO and Riverdale Country School ( **“Riverdale”** ) own and operate the Site located at [www.thepurposeproject.org](http://www.thepurposeproject.org/) and the associated mobile application (the “ **App** ”), which are collectively referred to as the “ **Purpose Project**.” 

**Account Creation:** If you login to the Purpose Project using Google OAuth, the following information from Google, if it has been made publicly available by you on Google, will be stored on our servers – ID, first and last names, email address, country, locale, and gender (“ **Purpose Project Login Information** ”). Additionally, your Google profile picture becomes part of your Purpose Project Login Information. Your Google ID will be your Username for the Site. 

**Deleting your Account:** If you wish to delete your Purpose Project account, you may do so by contacting us at [privacy@thepurposeproject.](mailto:privacy@thepurposeproject.org)[org](mailto:privacy@thepurposeproject.org) or at [privacynotice@ideo.com](mailto:privacynotice@ideo.com) and providing us with your Username. 

**The Purpose Project App** : When you visit the App, we collect some information automatically, such as your mobile device identifier (“ **Device ID** ”), IP address and operating system. We use the information that is automatically collected to support the internal operations of the App. Some types of internal operations include: 

  * to understand flow through the App; 
  * to reduce the repetition in the promotional messages that Users see on the App; and 
  * to understand what devices and operating systems the App is used on. 

**Other Corporate Entities** : We may share our data, including your Personal Information, Non-Identifying Information and Log Data, with Riverdale, and with Riverdale’s affiliates’ companies. To the extent that these entities have access to your information, they will treat it at least as protectively as they treat information they obtain from their Users. To the extent allowed by applicable law, these entities follow privacy practices that are no less protective of Users than the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

**_IDEO U_**

When you decide to join an IDEO U learning course, you will be asked to register for an account. Our IDEO U Site is administered and managed by our service provider, NovoEd.

**Where you are purchasing access to courses for other people:**

On registration and as part of sign up, you will have the opportunity to review this privacy policy. If you are purchasing for other people and therefore reviewing the contents of this policy on their behalf you warrant that you have the right to do so and they have also had the opportunity to accept and review the privacy policy. 

As part of the Course Registration process, you will be asked to provide us with your email address, payment information (including your billing address) and, optionally, your phone number. Course payments are processed via a third-party payment processor of your choice: PayPal or Shopify. We encourage you to review [Paypal](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) and [Shopify](https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy)’s privacy policies.

Personal information that NovoEd, collects for us during Account creation for IDEO U may include your name and email address. We strongly encourage you to review NovoEd’s [terms of service agreemen](http://novoed.com/terms/)t and [privacy policy](https://help.novoed.com/hc/en-us/articles/200047317-Privacy-Policy).

You may also choose to sign up through NovoEd with your social media profile (e.g., Facebook or Linkedin). When you engage with our or NovoEd’s content on or through third-party social networking sites, plug-ins and applications, you may allow us to have access to certain information from your social media profile (e.g., name, email address, photo, current position) to deliver the content or as part of the operation of the application. Through some social networking sites’ privacy settings, you can control what data you share. For more information about how social networking sites such as Linkedin or Facebook handle your Personal Information, please refer to their privacy policies and terms of use.

**Course Providers** : We may share Personal Information, Non-Identifying Information and Log Data with instructors who provide the courses on the IDEO U Site (" **Course Providers** "). They use this information mainly to provide, administer and improve courses and the services, to respond to your inquiries, and to analyze and conduct research on the services. 

**Your Employer** : If you are participating in IDEO U as part of an employer-sponsored program, at the request of your employer and as part of our agreement with them, we may provide your employer information about your activities and performance in connection with IDEO U, including contributions and performance information with respect to particular IDEO U courses or services (for Creative Difference your employer will have access to the email address associated with your User account information, but not your password or other Personal Information related to your User account such as your non-public contributions on the course). IDEO shall not be responsible or liable for the use of such information by your employer, and such use shall be subject to your employer's policies (including privacy policies) applicable to you. 

If you are an employer and have registered employees on their behalf to participate in IDEO U courses, you are liable for their actions and omissions and agree to indemnify IDEO for all losses and damages suffered as a result, including but not limited to breaches of this Privacy Policy.

**_Creative Difference_**

Creative Difference is IDEO’s creativity assessment tool. The login and registration processes for your IDEO Network Account in order to gain access to Creative Difference, along with our use of your Personal Information, are as stated above in the Section on your IDEO Network Account, unless you/your organization registered for Creative Difference prior to implementation of our IDEO Network Accounts.

If you are an admin for your organization’s Creative Difference assessment you will ensure that you have permission to provide email addresses of your organization’s assessment participants to IDEO for the purposes of distribution of the assessment. You understand that IDEO will email the Creative Difference assessment and other related notices to such participants from your organization. 

**Your Employer’s access to your Personal Information:** If you are participating in Creative Difference as part of an employer-sponsored program, at the request of your employer, your employer will have access to the email address associated with your User account information, but not your password or other information related to your User Account (such as your contribution to the assessment). IDEO shall not be responsible or liable for the use of such information by your employer, and such use shall be subject to your employer’s policies (including privacy policies) applicable to you

PRIVACY POLICY UPDATED AS OF SEPTEMBER 6, 2019
